it should come at no surprise that
having a consistent way to in trades
that gives you a positive expectancy
over time is going to be a pivotal part
of you becoming a profitable Trader if
you are missing this skill that it is
quite literally impossible for you to
ever make money as a Trader whereas on
the other side of that if you can Master
entries and master a consistent way to
get into trades that provides you with a
positive expectancy then that will be a
great first step to you becoming a
profitable Trader so in this video what
I'm going to do is share with you one of
the most profitable entries that I
personally use and I'm going to break
this down all the way to each and every
condition I look for along with the
actual reason that I press the buy or
sell button along with that I'll share
with you a few trades that I'm looking
at going into next week and give you a
full breakdown of the charts that I'm
paying attention to so if that sounds
good go ahead and click that like button
for me go ahead and subscribe if you are
new and we'll be right back after the
intro and
[Music]
disclaimer
before we dive into the charts and take
a look at this actual entry first I want
to go over the top three entry mistakes
that I see beginner and struggling
Traders make number one is that beginner
or struggling Traders most of the time
this is beginners tend to trade not even
based on a specific entry reason but
based on fear or greed let me give you
an example of what I'm talking about so
a beginner Trader may see something like
the market doing this and then decide oh
the market it's going up I need to
buy and they will buy based on nothing
more than greed because they want to
make money or fear fomo fear of missing
another move to the high side and what
happens more often than not is prices
then begin to drop and that Trader will
end up losing a lot of money now of
course the other side of that is that
Traders could be doing this and then
buying right here and sometimes yes
price will continue higher and they'll
feel like a genius but the truth is that
both of these are the wrong way to trade
because both of these Traders the one
that made money and the one that lost
money both of them were trading based on
fear or greed and not based on a
consistent pattern a consistent way of
trading that gives them an edge over
time so instead what we do as
professional Traders is we may trade
right here based on something called a
breakout but before we even do that
we're going to back test breakouts with
these exact rules that we've made up we
haven't made any up right now but what
I'm saying is you make up rules for a
strategy and then you take and back test
those rules in historic data now what if
you see that trading breakouts right
above a previous level of resistance
gives you about a 60% accuracy over the
latest 100 trades let's say and on
average you could get a 1.5 to1 rewarded
risk ratio well this is the recipe for a
profitable entry that you can now
utilize in your trading so now instead
of trading based on fear and greed
you're trading based on a proven entry
that you can use over and over and be
consistent with and throughout time if
you do this this is what creates profits
in a trading career so mistake number
one that I see all too often is beginner
and struggling Traders trading based on
Greed or fear mistake number two is that
I see a lot of Traders including myself
when I first started trading I honestly
thought that they was going to be an
entry reason I would find that would
make me 100% accurate I thought there
was just a Candlestick I didn't know or
maybe there was just a chart pattern
that I had not heard of yet and if I
learned that Candlestick pattern or
learned that chart pattern that I would
utilize it in markets and be able to win
100% of my trades and that could not be
further from the truth there is no
secret entry no Candlestick pattern no
chart pattern no secret indicator that's
going to cause you to win 80 to 100% of
your trades what we do instead of just
looking for that secret Candlestick
pattern or that secret chart pattern is
we combine a specific entry like
Candlestick patterns and chart patterns
with other technical conditions that
together equal a strategy and this
strategy is what makes us money over
time and finally number three is not
having specific rules for the reason you
press the buy or sell button what I mean
by that is you may have a lot of
different conditions you look for inside
of a strategy you look for the RSI
oversold you look for major levels of
structure you look for the macd to cross
but you don't really know exactly when
you're buying and exactly when you're
selling when are you going to press the
actual button to get inside of a trade
this is something that any successful
strategy must possess so with all that
said let's go ahead and dive into charts
and I'll show you the entry that I have
found to be the most profitable for me
so as I said an entry Reason by itself
doesn't mean much without having other
conditions so in other words any good
entry starts with the conditions you
look for beforehand so let's talk a
little bit about the conditions of the
entry that you're going to be learning
today first off we're going to be
looking for what we call an uptrend now
an uptrend put very simply is just when
prices are making new higher lows along
with making new higher highs now this
strategy that I'm going to be teaching
you today I utilize it on all different
time frames and it's a strategy that
makes use of multiple time frames so for
this example we're going to be going
from the daily to the 4H hour chart
meaning that our Trend and structure
analysis is going to happen on the daily
chart then we're going to move down to
the 4our to look for possible entries I
wanted to clear that up before we kept
going so this on the chart our uptrend
is the first thing we're going to be
looking for after we see this uptrend
we're going to wait for a pullback to
the previous level of resistance that
was broken now this is not all we need
to see we also need all of this to be
happening above the 50 period
exponential moving average so we can
tell that we are in fact in an uptrend
just makes it a little bit easier and
it's a great way to make this entry more
rules based so as long as this is
happening above the 50 EMA then we have
two of our conditions met the next
condition we're going to have is that
this level of structure must have been
tested at least twice so we need one two
times that price has either been pushed
down or pushed up from this level of
structure we need price to be in an
uptrend above the 50 EMA and we need to
see a pullback to this level of
structure that has been tested multiple
times now at this point all the
conditions are met and the next thing
we're going to talk about is the actual
entry reason and we're going to do that
on a chart in just a second first I want
to explain a bearish version of this to
ensure that it's extremely clear for a
bearish version of this entry nothing
changes except we're going in the
opposite direction so in this case we'd
be looking for lower highs and also
lower lows to form on price giving us
our downtrend after we see that we have
a downtrend we're going to be waiting
for price to push back up to the
previous level of support we want all of
this to be happening under the 50 EMA
and we want to ensure that this level
has been tested at least twice in the
past as a level of structure in this
case we have one two three tests of this
level we have price under the 50 EMA and
we have a confirmed downtrend with a
pull back to the previous level of
structure support giving us all the
conditions we need in order to start
looking for our actual entry reason
let's go ahead and take a look at a full
entry on a real chart so in terms of
conditions what is the first thing we
need to see the first thing that we're
looking for is an uptrend we have this
move here this move down this move back
up breaking into what at this point
we're breaking into what we call new
higher highs we also have a higher low
so this is in fact meeting our rule for
an uptrend what's another condition we
have before we look for the actual entry
reason which I'll go over in a second we
have to be above the 50 EMA by the way
this blue line is my 50 EMA this is
happening above the 50 EMA so that
condition is met the other condition is
that this level must to be a level
that's been tested multiple times is
that the case we have one test here we
have a test here here here so obviously
this is a level that's been tested
multiple times so now that we have all
the conditions met this is when we can
look for a rules-based way to enter the
market remember from the mistakes that I
talked about earlier it's important to
have rules around the actual reason you
hit the button so that's what we're
going to discuss right now to be clear
though this is what I would look for
beforehand my preemptive anoun is which
I will do with you a little later in the
video when I show you some of the pairs
I'm looking at for this exact strategy
but this would be my preemptive analysis
we be looking for this exact situation I
would put this pair on my watch list and
I would wait for a pullback into this
Zone and that's when I would look for an
actual entry reason luckily we have
Market replay so we don't have to look
we can just push price forward so as we
push price forward we come into our zone
now as I said this strategy this entry
utilizes two different time frames we
have the daily chart with we just
performed all of that analysis on I
personally am going to drop down to the
4H hour to look for an entry now if you
were looking at all your analysis Trend
and structure on the 4 Hour then what I
normally do is look for my entry on the
1 hour if I'm looking at Trend and
structure on the 1 hour I go down to the
15 minute chart for a possible entry so
on and so forth in terms of the
different time frames that I utilize
this strategy on but now that we are in
this Zone what do you think I'm going to
do I'm going to be dropping down to that
4-Hour chart now because I've utilized
conditions that already give me a pretty
good chance of success my entry reason
on these trades is very simple I look
for chart patterns in these zones on my
lower time frame what do I mean by that
in this specific case I'm going to be
looking for either a double bottom or a
head and shoulders pattern those are the
only two that I use for a bullish trade
and I guess it would be inverse Head and
Shoulders but you get the point you get
what I'm trying to say let's go a and
push the market forward and see what we
get and I'll show you the exact reason I
actually click the buy button on trades
like this so at this point right here we
have what I would consider a head and
shoulders pattern what do I mean by that
if you're new a head and shoulders
pattern is when we have a low followed
by a pullback followed by a lower low
followed by a near equal pullback to the
previous pullback and then we have what
we call the right shoulder which comes
down to a similar point of our previous
low all of this comes together to equal
what we call a head and shoulders
pattern this was my reason for entry and
the reason I actually clicked the buy
button is that after I got my head and
shoulder pattern what I look for is a
green candle just to show me buying
pressure I don't want to buy exactly at
this left shoulder after a big red
candle I want to see that buyers are
planning or at least have attempted to
take control based on my area of
structure based on the trend on the
daily chart and based on this head and
shoulders pattern along with Buyers just
trying to take control in general is
what gives me the confidence to place
trades so this green candle is exactly
why I would press the buy button on this
specific trade so as a quick recap
before we take a look at a bearish
version of this in these zones after all
the conditions are met that you have
learned throughout this video in these
zones I look for one of two things
double tops and bottoms or Head and
Shoulder SL inverse Head and Shoulder
patterns and in terms of the reason I
pressed the button is that after those
patterns when the patterns are still
valid I don't know why I did quotations
there but what I mean by still valid is
that if we would have had price pushed
down and a candle close way down here
and then we get a green candle that
obviously doesn't look like a head and
shoulders pattern anymore so as long as
the pattern is still valid and I get a
green candle showing buying pressure and
yes the size of the candle matters I
want to see buying pressure so I want to
see this candle B either a large candle
or have a pretty large Wick to the
bottom side showing me that buyers are
taking control at that point is when I
actually press the button now I'm going
to get out of Market replay mode for a
moment here and show you that I actually
took this trade at the moment I'm down
28 bucks on it because it's been
consolidating and it did not head higher
like I had hoped I was really hoping for
this head and shoulders pattern to push
the market higher but instead I bought
right at the top of that green candle
and since then price has Consolidated
but I did want to show you that I do
utilize exactly what you're learning in
this video to trade in my own accounts
and as you can see this is in fact a
live account right down here you can see
oanda live now a quick lesson before we
continue to looking at a bearish version
of this entry you may be sitting there
thinking oh Stephen what if you lose
that trade on the New Zealand dollar
well I have tested and traded this
specific entry enough to know that it
gives me about a 60% accuracy so with
that being the case that means I'm going
to lose about 40% of my trades and as we
talked about earlier in the video it's
not about having some perfect entry
that's going to win 100% of trades for
you it's about creating and molding a
full strategy around conditions and
entry reasons that gives you a positive
expectancy over time which is what this
strategy gives me so this positive
expectancy and understand understanding
it and having proper expectations along
with utilizing good risk management is
what keeps me comfortable and keeps me
confident even though I know there's a
possibility that I will lose this trade
this comes down to risk management as
well I'm okay losing this trade because
I'm okay with the amount that I'm
risking and because I know if I take
this trade over and over for the next
100 times it happens I will make money
at the end of that and so that gives me
a lot of relief and a lot less anxiety
and it keeps me from focusing on one
single trade which is something I think
is really important for beginner and
struggling traders to understand that is
the outcome of one single trade does not
matter and it should not matter because
your risk management should be so good
and so tight that it doesn't matter if
you lose one trade that's completely
fine and by the way that is going to
happen but what you should focus on is
the outcome of a large number of Trades
and you should focus on learning and
creating entries like the one you're
learning in this video that give a
positive expectancy over time that's
what's important when it comes to
entries now for a bearish example on the
charts so let me explain my preemptive
analysis in terms of a bearish trade
it's very similar to a bullish trade
just kind of upside down so for a
bearish example what I would be looking
for is price to make a new lower low
after making a lower or equal high this
is completely fine I still count this as
a downtrend now is this happening below
the 50 EMA yes it is that blue line is
my 50 EMA so with this happening below
the 50 EMA there's only one other
condition I need to look for in order to
wait for price to get in this Zone and
look for a possible entry reason what is
that other condition we have one test I
want to see multiple tests so I want to
see this area tested multiple times and
we do in fact get that with this test
right here so that would be the
preemptive analysis that's what I'm
looking for and then I'm putting this
pair on my watch list and I'm waiting
for price to get back into this Zone and
that's when I'll actually drop down down
to smaller time frames and look for
either a double top or a head and
shoulders pattern so now here on the
daily chart we pulled back up and we're
actually touching the zone that I was
looking in for a possible trading
opportunity with that being the case
what am I going to do I'm on the daily
chart now for me I'm going to be
dropping down to a 4-Hour chart to look
for a possible entry what am I going to
be looking for here either double tops
or a head and shoulders pattern so let's
go a and push the market forward and see
what happens the Candlestick you
currently see would be my actual entry
reason this would be the reason I would
hit the sell button and that is this red
candle with a wick to the top side and
it also meets my criteria for a
rules-based double top which means it's
a pattern where price hit the bodies of
the first top and did not close above
the wick of this first top as long as
that's the case I count this as a valid
double top so with all that coming
together the actual entry reason would
be the close of that red candle now I
actually go over stops and targets that
I normally utilize with this specific
entry as well I always like to try my
best to get my stop loss above the
entire Zone because price could play
around in this Zone and then drop and I
don't want to get stopped out
prematurely so with that being the case
the way this trade would look is
something like this I would have a stop
loss just above that zone because that's
going to make the stop loss pretty large
but in terms of trend continuation which
is what I'm actually utilizing here I'm
looking at the trend on the daily chart
and expecting that Trend to continue
what I know from past experience and
from the testing I've done is that
there's a pretty good chance on the
daily chart that if we see some
resistance from this level then we will
at least come all the way back down to
the previous lows and we may bounce up
and consolidate from there but there's a
pretty good chance that happens and
there's a slightly smaller chance but
still a decent chance that we'll go into
full-blown Trend continuation on the
daily chart and what entering on the 4H
hour chart on a smaller time frame does
is gives me the opportunity to use a
slightly smaller stop loss which
increases my reward to risk ratio so in
this case this is initially what that
trade would look like I'll go ahead and
click play as you can see price did in
fact play around and then eventually
push down into equal and even new lower
lows now to be completely honest I
probably would have got stopped out for
break even on this trade because the way
I manage trades is at a 1.4 to1 reward
to risk ratio I normally move my stop to
break even so in this case I would not
have been stopped out actually I thought
I would be but no in this case I would
have stayed in the trade what I normally
do in terms of managing positions and I
think this is a good lesson for beginner
and struggling Traders too fixed targets
are something that I utilized a lot at
the beginning of my trading career and
they're what I initially became
profitable with what I mean by fixed
targets is something like a 1.4 to1 or a
2: one and that's the fixed Target that
you have what I utilize in my trading
today and something that allows me to
get a lot more profit out of Trades is I
utilize a discretionary approach to
taking targets what I normally do is
wait for a 1.4 to1 to get hit by price I
move my stop loss to break even and then
I will manage the position by putting a
stop loss above the previous highs and
I'll look on higher time frames for the
next structure level down in order to
place my actual fixed Target but that my
friends is a little bit complicated for
you if you are either a beginner or
still struggling to be profitable but it
is something that you can learn and
something you will be able to do once
you gain a little more experience and
skill in trading now now I want to take
you through a few currency pairs that
I'm actually looking at for this exact
entry going into next week I'm going to
take you through essentially all of my
preemptive analysis for next week
utilizing this entry but before I do
that something I failed to mention is
that utilizing fixed targets is
completely fine when you're a beginner
and the reason that's the case is
because as a beginner or even a
struggling Trader you will likely make a
lot of mistakes when it comes to trying
to become discretionary or subjective
with your target taking you will likely
try to hold hold on to a trade too long
and it may end up coming back and you
may get stopped out of what should have
been a winning trade that's the reason I
utilized fixed targets at the beginning
of my trading career because I was not
experienced or skilled enough to use
discretion in my target taking but just
like anything else with experience you
will get better at this with practice
you will get good enough to be able to
take discretionary targets and for that
to be a beneficial part of your trading
whereas at the very beginning of your
trading career or if you're still
struggling that made not be the best
idea and to go along with that this
strategy may look a little intimidating
just because of the fact that
identifying structure levels is
subjective there are no set and stone
rules for exactly how big the Zone
should be or exactly where the Zone
should be but just like with Target
taking the more you back test the more
you practice on a demo account and the
more experience you gain with this you
will eventually become like a sniper
when it comes to pointing out these
zones of important structure before
looking for entries inside of them so I
actually have three currency pairs that
I'm paying attention to for this exact
entry and right now what I'm going to do
is show you all those pairs and kind of
walk you through all my preemptive
analysis when utilizing this entry we're
going to start off on the pound dollar
here on this pair this is a super ahead
of time analysis but on this pair kind
of what I'm looking for and what I want
to see is I want to see price push up
and break Above This level I'll leave
that line there to make that clear but
if that does in fact to happen check out
what we have we have a uptrend with new
higher lows along with new higher highs
we have this happening above the 50 EMA
and if I put a horizontal line on the
screen and create this zone for you you
will see that we also have if we do in
fact get price breaking Above This level
a level that's been tested multiple
times so those are the conditions I look
for before looking for an actual entry
what I mean by that is throughout the
next week or two what I'm going to be
looking for on the the pound dollar is
to see if price can come back into this
Zone if we get a break above it and
provide me with an entry reason
utilizing the chart patterns we've
talked about in this video the double
bottom and or head and shoulder pattern
inside of this area so I know that's
super preemptive but that's what I'm
paying attention to on the pound dollar
next up we have the Canada Swiss here on
the Canada Swiss what kind of trend are
we in hopefully you said we're in a
downtrend and if you did you would be
correct we have a new lower high
compared to our previous High we also
have a new lower low compared to our
previous low all this is happening below
my blue line which is the 50 period
exponential moving average and what is
the next condition I want to see that
the level that was just broken has been
tested multiple times and in this case
that does in fact happen so with that
being the case what I'm looking for
right now on the Canada Swiss is I'm
waiting for a pullback into this Zone
when it gets here what do I want to see
I'm going to want to see either a double
top or a head and shoulder pattern
inside of this area in order to inform
me that we could possibly see some
selling pressure and see a continuation
of this downtrend on the daily chart I'm
going to utilize a smaller time frame
which will give me the ability to have a
smaller stop- loss and hopefully get a
really big reward to risk ratio on this
trade if it does in fact occur next up
we're going to look at the Euro Aussie
on this pair it's slightly different
than the other two because I'm utilizing
the previous resistance as my resistance
level instead of the prev support this
is something else I do but I didn't have
time to explain in this video but it's a
very similar concept essentially we're
looking for a level of structure that's
been tested multiple times while price
is in a downtrend below the 50 EMA all
that does in fact occur here so at this
point on the Euro Aussie what I'm
actually looking for because we're
already in our Zone here as you can see
what I'm actually looking for is I'll be
looking on the 4H hour chart over the
next week or so it's currently Friday at
like 3:00 a.m. when I'm recording this
so this may happen today at some point
but if it doesn't then next week I'll be
looking for either a double top in this
zone or a possible head and shoulder
pattern in this Zone and if that does in
fact occur and I get a reason for entry
then this is a trade I'll be looking at
so feel free to keep an eye on these
currency pairs throughout the next week
or two to see what happens when it comes
to this exact entry now something I hope
you noticed is that throughout this
video what I tried my best to do is
point out the top three problems that I
see beginner and struggling Traders
having with entries which are trading
and entering the market based on Greed
or fear instead of a proven to be
profitable entry reason expecting an
entry reason like a Candlestick pattern
or chart pattern to be 100% accurate or
not having rules at all for the exact
reason they hit the buy or sell button
the exact reason they enter the market
so I wanted to point those out so that
you are aware of them but also provide
you the information that helps you fix
those mistakes so if you think that I
did that go ahead and click that like
button for me go And subscribe if you're
new make sure to comment if you made it
to the end or if you're a
bot sorry I couldn't help it there if
you know you know if not don't worry
about it at all that's going to do it
for this video I wish you the best of
luck on all your future trades I hope
you trade green and I'll talk to you in
the next video see you soon